Hello, I'm Kyle Brayer, and your next in-home tricep exercise will be the tricep drop set.
This can be performed standing or seated in a kitchen chair or bench.
Karie's going to start with a 10 lb. dumbbell here. She's going to pick it up over her head, just as she did on the overhead tricep extensions.
The exercise here is to fatigue the triceps, so the idea is to get as many repetitions as possible.
So Karie will start with these 10 lbs., keeping perfect form, she's going to go up and over her head.
As she starts to fatigue, as she starts to get tired we're going to be looking at this 5 lb. medicine ball.
So let's say that she does 6 or 7 repetitions and she starts to fatigue.
She's going to bring that weight up and over her head, back down to her thighs safely.
Okay, Karie, here you go, and I'll trade you with the medicine ball.
So she's going from 10 lbs.
to 5 lbs., and now she's going to perform the same exercise up and over her head.
She's going to do the same thing until she fatigues.
So she's really working the triceps right now, and since we're doing so many repetitions and we're dropping the weight, we're adding a lot of blood and amino acids into those muscles that will help fatigue them.
There you go, Karie, and then last we'll give her a 3 lb.
medicine ball.
So as you start out, 3 different weights is a good way to start.
As you progress, you can actually, from the gym start at like the 25s and work your way all the way down to the 5 lb.
dumbbells.
As you get more advanced you can play with the weights and start heavier, start lighter.
The idea is when she's done with these she'll almost reach failure, so she'll be pressing until she can no longer press the weight anymore.
That's good.
So this an overhead tricep drop set.